Cornelia Marschall Smith papers, Inclusive: 1915-2006, undated, Bulk: 1960-1988, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Cornelia Marschall Smith papers
Inclusive: 1915-2006, undated, Bulk: 1960-1988, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
666
Smith, Cornelia Marschall
10 document boxes and one oversized box
The Cornelia Marschall Smith papers contain materials from her time at Baylor University, both as a student and professor, and time from her tenure at Stetson University in Florida. Also included are personal materials that include programs, invitations, copies of a manuscript, photographs, negatives, slides and postcards.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Cornelia Marschall Smith was born 1895 October 15 on a ranch in Llano County, Texas, the youngest of four children of Lucy and Ernst Marschall. Cornelia attended public schools in Llano, finishing high school in three years. She then pursued a State Teacher's Certificate and taught at a private one-teacher school for one year.
In 1915, Cornelia entered the pre-med program at Baylor University and graduated in 1918. She accepted a position at Waco High School upon graduation and taught biology there until 1925. While teaching high school, Cornelia completed the requirements for the Master's program in botany at the University of Chicago, finishing in 1923. It was in 1923 that Cornelia met Professor Charles G. Smith whom she married in 1926. Cornelia then entered Johns Hopkins University where she received her PhD in biology in 1928.
In the fall of 1928, Cornelia was appointed Assistant Professor of Botany at Baylor University, where she taught General Biology, Bacteriology, Methods of Teaching Biology, and other courses. Her husband, Charles, was also a professor of English at Baylor during this time. In 1930, however, Baylor instituted a policy prohibiting a husband and wife from both teaching at Baylor. This led Cornelia to give up her position as professor and take up research. She studied in Baylor's English department and maintained her own research schedule in botany.
In 1935, the Smiths moved to John B. Stetson University where Cornelia served as Chairman of the Botany Department and Charles served as Dean of the University. Their appointment at John B. Stetson lasted until 1940 when Baylor President Pat Neff asked the couple to return to Baylor, with Cornelia as Professor of Botany until 1943, when she became Chair of the Botany Department and Curator of the Strecker Museum. She served in this capacity until 1967. For almost a quarter of a century, Cornelia Marschall Smith instructed all pre-med and pre-dental students who enrolled at Baylor.
Cornelia held numerous positions during her tenure at Baylor, both within the university and within the community. The governor appointed her to the State Board of Examiners in the Basic Sciences in 1949, and she was their secretary-treasurer until she retired in 1967. In 1959, she was a part of the committee to formulate and initiate Baylor's Honors program. She was also a member of the pre-med and pre-dental advisory committee. In 1965, she was appointed chairman of the committee to plan the biology section of the new Sid Richardson Science Building. Cornelia was also the faculty advisor to Beta Tau Chapter of Beta, Beta, Beta, the National Honorary Biological Society, was voted Outstanding Woman Faculty Member of Baylor in 1963 and Teacher of the Year in 1966. In 1972, she was voted Outstanding Baylor Alumni and in 1980, Baylor initiated the Cornelia M. Smith Professorship in her honor.
Cornelia's community interests were also wide-ranging. She was a member of the Daughters of the Republic of Texas, the American Association of University Professors, American Association of University Women, Modern Language Association, Texas Ornithological Society, Central Texas Chapter of the National Audubon Society, American Society of Zoologist, North Texas Botanical society, and the American Institute of Biological Sciences. Along with these organizations, she also worked in the Waco community on boards and committees such as the McLennan County Unit of the American Cancer Society, Waco Garden Club, and was a charter and lifetime member of the Historic Waco Foundation. She was also instrumental in establishing the Waco Symphony Association.
Cornelia continued to be involved with Baylor University and the Waco community after her retirement in 1967. She lived to be 101 years old, passing away in 1997 August, and is buried at Oakwood Cemetery in Waco, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Cornelia Marschall Smith papers range in date from 1915 to 1995, with the bulk of the papers from 1960 to 1988. The first series in the collection, Baylor, consists of material from Smith's time at Baylor University, both as a student and as a professor. Series II., Personal Materials, contains items pertaining to Smith's personal life and diverse interests such as organizations she was affiliated with and awards she received. Correspondence, the third series in the papers, contains correspondence to and from Smith, and is comprised of both personal and professional correspondence. The fourth series, Subject Files, is also the largest in the papers and represents those files Smith considered miscellaneous in her arrangement and which she foldered and kept separately.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection was arranged in folders with titles and some original order. This arrangement was maintained where possible. The collection is now arranged in four series: I. Baylor, II. Personal Materials, III. Correspondence, and IV. Subject Files.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 666. Acquired 1974-04-00
Related Resources
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. "Caroline Cornelia Marschall Smith." Memorial #97250074. Databases. Accessed 2019 October 9.
Baylor University. "Celebrating Cornelia Marschall Smith." 1982 November 5. Cornelia Marschall Smith papers #666, Box 1 Folder 11, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Browning, Robert, 1812-1889 -- Language.; Smith, Cornelia Marschall, 1895-.
Subjects (Organizations)
Strecker Museum -- History.
Subjects
Baylor University -- Faculty.; Botany -- Study and teaching (Higher); Postcards.; Proverbs in literature -- Indexes.
Genres
Business correspondence.; Certificates.; Course materials.; Invitations.; Negatives (Photographs); Personal correspondence.; Photographs.; Programs (Publications).; Publications (documents).; Slides (photographs)
- Baylor, 1915-2006, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Baylor series contains materials from Cornelia Marschall Smith's time at Baylor University, both as a student and then as a professor. Notes, invitations, programs, course work, photographs, and publications are all included in this section. The condition of the series is good.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  35 mm slide; Photo negative; Photographic print
  - 50th Year Golden Anniversary Graduate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barnes, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baylor Bulletin, Patriotic Number, Vol. XXI, Nos 5 &6, 1918 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baylor Invitations and Ephemera, 1915-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baylor News Clippings, 1965-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beta Beta Beta, Beta Tau Appreciation Album (1 of 3), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beta Beta Beta, Beta Tau Appreciation Album (2 of 3), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beta Beta Beta, Beta Tau Appreciation Album (3 of 3), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Birds in Winter — Slides, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Books Donated to Moody Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Celebrating Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Charles F. and Cornelia Marschall Smith Trust, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class Notes: Chaucer and Shakespeare, 1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornelia Marschall Smith Professorship, 1981-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Early copy of The Physical Browning, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Faculty and Friends Who Have Received Browning’s Proverb Lore, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Invitations, Programs, 1914-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Insectivores, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Junior/Senior Class Minutes, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Last Copy of The Physical Browning, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letters to and from Publishers, 1976-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Materials on President White’s First Wife’s Dress, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Orchids, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “Pat Neff at Sunset”, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy, 1974-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Physical Browning with Dr. Reynold’s edits, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Physical Browning—Arkansas State University, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Printout of Various Proverbs (1 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Printout of Various Proverbs (2 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Printout of Various Proverbs (3 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Printout of Various Proverbs (4 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - R.C. Burns Review of The Physical Browning, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Retired Professor Center Newsletter, 1984 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Senior Lists, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sigma Xi, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Strecker Museum, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Strecker Museum: Oral History, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tenure at Baylor, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Arrist Pen Browning: A Monograph by Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Venus Fly Trap, 1991 April-1992 April, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wild Edible Plants—Slides, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wildflowers—Slides, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Yucca Materials, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dedication of the Dr. A.J. Armstrong Memorial Plaque, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Personal Materials, 1918-1995, undated; 2
  The Personal Materials series contains items pertaining to Smith's personal life and diverse interests such as organizations she was affiliated with and awards she received. Included here are correspondence, certificates, invitations, programs, biographical material, and information on the Marschall family who founded Fredericksburg, Texas. This series also contains a postcard collection. The materials are in good condition.
  35 mm slide; Photo negative; Photographic print; Postcards
  - American Biographical Institute, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Article: Botany, by Sereno Watson, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Article on Charles G. Smith, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Booklets, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Birthday Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Birthday Party, 1981 October 15 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Account of Dr. Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book Plates, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Camp Swannona, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Certificates, 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Christmas Cards, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: The Ring and the Book (1 of 3), 1940-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: The Ring and the Book (2 of 3), 1940-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: The Ring and the Book (3 of 3), 1940-1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Feber McMullen, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fences, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Florida Wild Flowers, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Invitations and Certificates, 1956, 1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Legal Documents, 1922, 1972-1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - LeMaster, Lon—Article and Poem, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Life History: Cornelia M. Smith, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Life Insurance Policies, 1921-1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Manhattan School of Music, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript: Browning’s Proverb Lore, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Marianne Scruggs Garden Club of the Dallas Woman’s Club Yearbook, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - “Memoirs of my Life in Llano, Texas,” by Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Memorials by Ted Egri, 1978-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. J.B. Smith, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oral History: Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photographs (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: 1918 Class Photograph Album, circa 1918 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Christmas, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Texas Board of Examiners in Basic Sciences, Galveston, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Poems and Clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Postcards: California, Nevada, Utah (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Postcards: California, Nevada, Utah (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Postcards: Connecticut, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Postcards: General, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Postcards: Massachusetts, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Postcards: New York, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Postcards: Pennsylvania, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cornelia's Life: Articles and Clippings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1920, 1922, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Program: Forsyth Dental Infirmary for Children, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - “Proverbs in The Ring and the Book”, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - “Scientific Creationism: A Controversy Unraveled,” by Dr. Bob Patterson, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Slides, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Texas Academy of Science, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Texas Academy of Science Annual Meeting, Dallas, TX, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Texas Committee on Natural Resources, Ned Fritz, Chairman, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - “Texas Forever”, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The John Hopkins University Letter of Congratulations, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tour Materials, 1920, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Travel, 1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Who’s Who in America, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Who’s Who in the World, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pi Lamda Theta-Irene Marschall, 1923 June 25 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Magistri in Artibus Siberalibus-Irene Marschall von Bieberstein, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Bachelor of Arts Degree, Baylor University-Irene Marschall, 1916 June 7 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Sigma Xi, Associate Membership-Cornelia Marschall, 1923 November 24 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Fellow of the Texas Academy of Science-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1929 November 29 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Beta Tau Chapter, Beta Beta Beta Fraternity membership-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1931 May 15 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Daughters of the Republic of Texas-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1935 March 2 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Bachelor of Arts Degree, Baylor University-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1918 June 5 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Athenian Club Program, 1957 Spring (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Diamond Anniversary Diploma, Baylor University-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1993 March 22 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - State of Texas Senate Commendation-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1995 October 15 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - The Presidents Club Charter Membership, Baylor University-Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Waco Tribune Herald Article: "Former Biology Chairman Prefers Miind Over Matter", 1979 September 3 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Book Covers: "Browning's Proverb Lore", undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - "Paul Revere and The Boston of His Time", undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - Johns Hopkins Diploma, Doctor of Philosophy-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1928 June 12 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - Texas State Teacher's Permanent Certificate-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1921 June 8 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - University of Chicago Diploma, Masters in Science-Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 18)
  - Black and White Photograph, 11.5 x 16, Dr. Charles G. Smith, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 19)
  - Black and White Photograph, 11.5 x 16, Dr. Cornelia Marschall Smith, undated (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook, 100th Birthday-Cornelia Marschall Smith, 1995 (Box 11 OVZ, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1918-1990, undated; 3
  This series contains correspondence sent to Cornelia Marschall Smith from 1918-1990 with some undated materials. The correspondence is comprised of both professional and personal materials. The documents are in good condition.
  Photo negative; Photogravure print
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence (1 of 4), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (2 of 4), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (3 of 4), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (4 of 4), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Subject Files, 1929-1994, undated; 4
  The Subject Files series represents those files Smith considered miscellaneous in her arrangement and which she foldered and kept separately. The topics range from information dealing with Baylor University to personal associations and memberships.This section also contains materials on Smith's genealogy. The series is in good condition.
  Photo negative; Photographic print
  - Alpha Epsilon Delta, 1929-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Africa Week and Africa, 1977-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Armstrong, A.J. (Material), 1945-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Baptist Foundation of Texas, 1982 October 8 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Baylor Line, 1986 June 4 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Baylor Line Press, 1988 October 21 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ben B. White, MD—“The Cycle of History”, 1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Big Thicket: Pileated Woodpecker (print), 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Big Thicket, 1986 May-September, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Biology Department Faculty—Magnifier and Memoirs, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Birds and Cards, 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Brazos Forum, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brooks, Samuel Palmer: Book Plates, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - “Browning’s Proverb Lore” Press Responses, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Browning, Robert—General, 1988 May (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Burns, Robert Grant, 1978, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Burglary, 801 James, 1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Burns, Robert Grant: Forward to “The Keeper of Juno’s Swans”, circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Bruhl, Elaine Price, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Cancer, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Carter, Rosalyn, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Charles G. and Cornelia Marschall Smith Awards, 1976-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Charles G. and Cornelia M. Smith at Stetson University, Florida, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - “Chemical Evolution”, 1969-1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Christmas Card: Dallas Museum of Art, 1976 December (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Colored Plates of Birds and Leaves, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Commencement 1981: Pictures with Mace (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Longer, Roger: ‘Lasca,” Edition Limited to 300 Idea for Monograph, circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Concordia, circa 1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cornelia M. Smith Bird Nest Collection, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Vitae: Frazier, 1986 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Distinguished Lecturers, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - E-OK: Energy-Efficient Homes, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Edmondson, E. Bud, M.D.: Personal Data, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Engleman, George, 1982-1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Letters: Etkind, Irving, M.D., 1986 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Evolution (empty folder), undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - European Relatives, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fellowship ’87: Jack Kilgore, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Founders Day Celebration and Dedication of Texas Historical Marker at Marschall-Muesebach Cemetery, Cherry Springs, Texas, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Founders Day: Comanche Springs (empty folder), undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Founders Day: Fredericksburg, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Franklin, Ed N., D.D.S: Personal Data, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gaines, Richard: Recommends The Multiple Sclerosis Diet Book, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Geology, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Ginko Tree, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gould, Ilse and Lloyal, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Guest Lists, 1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Harvard University Press, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Heritage Club, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Historic Foundation Waco, 1986-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Honors Program, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - House: Sale—400 Baker Lane, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - House: Repairs—801 James, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - House: Closet—801 James, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Immigrants Landing, Fredericksburg, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - India Week, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Johnson, Patricia: “Striking Out Against Fat,” and “34 Types of Plants to Replace Fuel Products”, 1975-1978, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Kappa Epsilon Alpha Banquet: Charles G. Smith and E.H. Sparkman, Sponsors, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma, 1989 October (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Irene Marschall King, 1970-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - King, Irene M: Letters For, 1975-1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - King, Irene Marschall, Letters from Uncle Fritz, 1931 July 7 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Irene’s (King) Memorial, 1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - King, Roma A., undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Landman, Sidney: Material for Armstrong-Browning Library, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - LeAnne Smith, 1988 January-March (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Letters and Sonnets by Charles G., Quotes, and Poem by Uncle Bob Paschal, “O Texas Land”, 1932-1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Letter of Activities, 1986 June-July (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Letters to J.B. Smith, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Llano County Historical Society: Originals, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Llano Memoirs, 1944-1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Llano Memoirs: Criticisms, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Llano Memoirs: Revisions, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Llano Museum, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)